Often there can be a bit of shock when you look at your paycheck and see the gross pay
amount, the amount before deductions, compared to the net pay amount, the amount of money
you actually get.
What is all that money that is being subtracted?
Let's dig into paycheck deductions a little more so we can get a better understanding of
what those amounts that are being deducted actually are.
First, we have income tax.
By law, an employer must deduct the amount of federal and provincial income tax you're
likely to over the year and submit it to the government on your behalf.
Taxes go towards things like roads, schools, parks and hospitals.
You may also see Canada Pension Plan or CPP.